Oh, when someone says,
“you’re high,”
it means they think
you’re a gentleman.
Well then…
I am indeed high.
Carmelita! Juanito!
What is the meaning of this?
Carmelita couldn’t hold it in.
She needs to go now.
It has only been six months
since my brother left,
but there are already rumors
that you are meeting someone new.
I believe that you
and Miss Carmelita don’t have
any kind of relationship.
But Don Alejandro would
not be pleased about it.
He wants you to clear Carmelita’s name.
Marry her.
I just want to say that,
I think it’s for the
better if she would bear
many children for Juanito.
- Isn’t that right, son?
- You’re quite right, Mother.
I heard something about you.
I heard Carmelita is quite
adept at playing the piano?
Your friend is sick, isn’t she?
That is why I asked you to come
so you can visit Helena.
Miss Helena,
Miss Carmelita is here to see you.
How are you?
What are you doing here?
This is for you.
I just wanted to see
how you’re doing.
Me?
You’re worried about me?
What for?
Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
You and Juanito are set to get married.
Helena, the thing is…
It was only yesterday that
my brother was your lover.
And now, you turned to Juanito?
You know well how long
I had these feelings
for Juanito, right?
Believe me.
It was just an accident when
they caught us
under the mango tree.
I was just looking
for my sister, Maria.
How can I be sure you
have no feelings for Juanito?
Because...
Because I'm still in love with
Leonardo-- I mean, Leandro.
I want to rest now.
Helena...
I don't want to lose another friend,
just like what happened
between me and Shae.
I'll go ahead.
But I hope
you'll believe me
when I say I don't want the wedding
to push through.
Hmm?
OMG!
What's Juanito doing here
in the Flores residence?
Wait... is he looking for Helena?
So, they have mutual feelings.
They are in love.
My friend, we'll be heading now.
Thank you.
Until next time, my friend.
Thank you very much, Captain Flores.
Dear Diary.
Now I realize that not everything
that was written in this diary is true.
Not all of Grandma Carmina
and Mother Olivia's stories are factual.
The truth is only Carmelita
fell in love with Juanito.
And Juanito has
feelings for someone else.
Completely confused, Carmela.
I have to plan everything
smoothly in order to stop all of this.
First, I have to save Juanito.
To stop the tragedy,
Helena and Juanito
must become closer.
Which is actually not that difficult
since they already have
feelings for each other.
Second,
I need to...
I need to think of a reason
for Don Alejandro
and Don Mariano...
To stop them from pushing
this arranged marriage.
But I can't think of anything!
Yes, come in.
Miss,
your mother has sent
these books for you.
So that you may read it immediately.
What is all these books
Carmelita has been reading?
I don't even like reading.
Do you need anything else, Miss?
Are you sure about what you're
planning to do, Miss Carmelita?
Shh.
They might hear you say my name.
Don't say it.
And yes, I'm sure of it.
No one can stop me.
But...
how did you know that that
window is the room of Mr. Juanito?
Of course. I saw him
looking out there earlier.
I'll go ahead.
Shush.
- Miss, please be careful!
- Shush! Shush!
Miss! Please be careful!
In fairness,
his room is clean and tidy.
And what's this?
Leccion de clinica cor... oh!
Whatever!
These books are thick.
Too thick.
Who are you?
Miss!
Don't you dare look!
OMG!
Miss Carmelita?
What are you doing here?
How did you get in?
There. Through the window.
Through the window?
How did you come up here?
What if something happened to you?
Are you hurt?
No biggie.
I can easily climb through a window.
Basic.
No biggie? Basic?
Miss, why are you speaking this way?
Shh.
I just want to be unique.
Just keep this between us.
It's our secret. Okay?
Miss-- Miss, you can't be there!
- You can't be there!
- Huh?
Miss, why are you here?
My father might catch us.
Also, how did you leave your home?
I'm sure Don Alejandro
wouldn't have permitted you.
Chill.
Just chill.
First of all, there's something
important I have to tell you. And...
And... secondly...
Don't worry.
My father won't catch me
because I'm quite good at this.
And thirdly...
You know what they say.
"If you want it,
there's always a way."
So that's why I found a
way to get out of the house.
Miss, I still don't understand
what you're doing here?
Juanito.
Oh, right. I shouldn't
touch him without reason.
Long hair suits you
very well, dear sister.
Do you remember?
You and Carmelita always
have the same hairstyle.
We have many similarities
when we were younger.
But you're not children anymore.
You cannot share
every single thing.
Especially when it comes to love.
And to the man you wish
to be your husband.
Miss,
what is this urgent
thing you mean to tell me
that couldn't wait tomorrow?
You really need to know this.
I don't want to waste
time as well. Besides…
I still couldn't sleep.
It's too early.
My back hurts from climbing the window.
Oh, wait. People here are conservative!
He might think I'm seducing him.
I'm a bit drunk,
that's why I'm impulsive.
You don't smell like liquor.
OMG! Why did he smell me?
I haven't bathed yet! So embarrassing!
You read Noli Me Tangere too, huh?
Miss Carmelita,
what is it you wanna tell me?
Carmelita promised me.
That she will not push
through with the wedding.
And you believed her?
Carmelita is my friend.
How can you be sure
of your friend's promise?
Promises are easily broken.
Or forgotten.
But there's a thing that isn't
easily broken or forgotten.
What is it you're thinking of?
I will write to Leandro.
I also know that you don't want
this wedding to push through, right?
Let's help each other.
And how can you be sure that
this wedding is against my wishes?
Your heart belongs to Helena, right?
I will help you out.
Helena is in love with you.
This wedding is important
to both our families.
I do not want to go against my father
and neither should you.
You mustn't go against him.
How about your heart?
And how about your dreams?
You're just gonna let other people
dictate the course of your life?
You're Helena's crush, and
you have a crush on Helena.
You like each other.
I don't want to go between you.
What are you talking about?
All I'm saying is that
we should avoid situations
we don't want to be in.
I know for sure Helena likes you.
And I don't want our friendship
to end just because of a guy.
What's the reason
why you don't want
this wedding to happen?
Hello? I can't tell him that he'll die
if our wedding pushes through.
Just so!
I don't want to be
controlled by other people.
Your principles are important to
you, so it seems, Miss Carmelita.
Just don't worry anymore, okay?
I will help you and Helena.
On one condition.
Promise me,
no matter what happens,
you'll survive.
He needs to survive for me
to accomplish my mission.
Juanito!
Angelito!
Miss!
- Miss!
- Shush!
Run! Just run!
What are you doing here?
I just want to ask you to tutor me.
How about them?
Why are they here?
Did something happen last night,
Carmelita?
Huh?
You're in such a good mood,
you even cooked breakfast.
You're really preparing
for a married life.
It's different once a person falls in love.
It's different if a person
has no other choice.
Carmelita, we still haven't prayed.
That's right. I noticed they
always pray before meals.
Bless us, O Lord, this food
we are about to receive,
and those who prepared it...
Amen.
I envy Carmelita's family.
Dad, Jenny, Emily and I
don't pray before meals.
We don't even eat together
because Dad leaves early
and does overtime at night.
On times we do eat together,
we're all glued to our phones.
Carmelita, isn't this what
you like to eat for breakfast?
As far as I know, we
don't eat this for breakfast.
It's usually cereal, pancake,
toasted bread, bacon and eggs.
- Here you go.
- Carmelita.
Your coffee's getting cold.
I noticed you haven't
been drinking coffee lately.
It's because I don't drink black coffee.
I just forgot about it, Father.
Salted egg?
I'm sure Carmelita will eat
them all. That's her favorite!
Ew. I've never tried
this in my whole life.
Carmelita and I
are total opposites.
Here you go.
Don't you have an appetite, Carmelita?
I do.
Hmm.
Not bad!
It's surprisingly delicious!
Good morning,
Don Alejandro, Doña Soledad.
- Good morning.
- Ladies.
Miss Carmelita.
Oh no! Why is he here?
Is he ratting me out?
Juanito, dear boy. What can you
say about Carmelita's kaldereta?
It's like no other.
Huh? Josefina helped me
in cooking this.
You know, Juanito.
Carmelita is naturally
a fine, respectable lady.
She never disobeyed her father.
Juanito.
Run! Just run!
It is true that Miss Carmelita
is a gentle and desirable lady.
She also likes reading
books and sewing.
She is also quite
adept at house work.
And she never complains to anyone.
Carmelita, after eating you must
show Juanito around the hacienda.
This guy charmed my family.
How are you feeling?
May I check your condition?
Is that why you brought me here?
Because you thought I got injured
from climbing your window?
My God, come on.
That's nothing to me.
And in case I got injured,
why would you bother to check?
If you haven't realized from the books
you saw on my room...
I am a student of medicine.
So, this jerk is a medical student, huh?
Oh, really. That's nice.
Wait, why would I respond that way?
Carmelita would look
clueless about the world.
Where are we going, by the way?
Why, you don't like it here?
Would you prefer the Lake of Tears?
Oh, no. That lake has a bad story.
Huh?
There's an elder
who told the story of a
brokenhearted woman
who once cried there unconsolably...
Until the moment of her death.
All the tears she had shed
filled the Lake of Tears.
It is saddening
that the story of that lake became reality
when Carmelita drowned herself in there.
I will make sure from now on
that no other woman
will die in that lake from now on.
I will make sure that Carmelita
won't suffer the same fate...
because of you, Juanito.
You seem quite
absorbed in your thoughts.
Have you been in love as well?
You're used to get whatever you want.
You don't care if anyone gets hurt.
I apologize if you
don't want to share.
I do not mind.
Let's just say,
I have bad luck in love.
Of all the boys in the world...
I just had to give
my heart to him.
There's no such thing
as bad luck in love.
And there's no wrong person to love.
Maybe the timing wasn't just right...
When you fell in love.
Or maybe we're
just not meant to be.
Where is he right now?
Maybe he's thinking that my first love
is just in the next village, or city.
He's somewhere far away.
No one can ever come there.
I'm not even sure if
I will see him again.
I didn't even get to
say that I like him.
I'm sure...
that even if you weren't able to say it,
he knows what you feel.
And deep in his heart...
You're the one it belongs to.
If only Juanito knew
that I'm talking about
James from the future.
But in fairness, I feel better
because of what he said.
Is there anything I can
do to make you feel better?
What's happening? My heart beat...
Not for me.
For my friend, Helena.
I want you to get closer.
How did you two meet?
We write letters.
What did you like about her?
Why does it seems like
Helena is more important to you?
Is our wedding not your priority?
How about the wishes of your family?
Come on,
we can just ignore
what our parents want.
Don't tell me
you're just blindly following
your parents' orders all your life?
How about what you want?
Do you even like medicine?
Nothing else?
You don't find joy in anything else?
What are you good at?
I like painting.
- Oh?
- And drawing.
See? Then do that.
That's what will make you happy.
Why don't you paint me?
That'll be cool.
Don't you think?
Thank you for accepting
my invitation to stroll around.
No worries, I enjoyed...
It made me glad too.
The air's fresh.
By the way...
Is this for me?
A letter. For Helena.
I'm hoping she can receive it.
Alright. I'll handle it.
I'll be going then, Miss.
Miss, Dona Soledad
is looking for you.
She said you're going to be
doing embroidery with your sisters.
Is that so?
Can you give this to Helena?
I got it.
Thank you.
Oh!
Thank you very much, Carmelita!
Please forgive me for misunderstanding.
Now I see your true intentions.
Thank you.
Don't you worry about it.
As long as you and Juanito are happy.
Good thing the
misunderstanding was cleared.
I don't want to ruin her
friendship with Carmelita.
Here's my reply to
Juanito's letter yesterday.
I'll be going now.
Helena.
Can we chat even for a little bit?
There's just some things I want to ask.
Like what?
Like... your interests?
- What?
- Oh, right.
Helena and
Carmelita are best of friends.
She might be confused
why I'm asking.
Well, uh...
I forgot about a few things and
also I want to pass it on to Juanito.
Carmelita, my dear child.
Married life is not easy.
In a few months,
you'll be a wife.
And we don't know, maybe soon you
and Juanito will be blessed with child.
Juanito has almost completed
his study of medicine.
And I'm sure he'll be busy with his job.
And you will be busy
with your tasks at home.
You will cook, shop,
clean the house.
And you will be taking
care of your children.
And you will also bring
pleasure to your husband.
Bring pleasure? Am I
really ready for all of this?
That's why I'm going to
teach you as early as now.
I noticed that you haven't
been yourself lately.
Does she know that I
am not really Carmelita?
Good day, Dona Soledad.
Miss Carmelita.
Why are you here?
Good day to you as well, Juanito.
I am glad to see you here today.
When I visited your home,
I was informed that
you will be here in town.
I do not have anything
important to do today,
that is why I've decided
to accompany you.
If you would allow me.
You didn't need to be here.
I wanted to see you and
spend time with you, Miss.
There he goes again.
My heart is beating so fast.
Am I feeling nervous, or what?
Very well.
Juanito, Carmelita, I
will do my shopping now.
I will leave the two of you.
Do not worry, Dona Soledad.
I'll take good care of your daughter.
Don't call me Dona anymore.
I think it would be better
if you would just call me...
"mother."
From now on.
Yes, mother.
I'll be going then.
What's wrong with you?
You shouldn’t be cozying up to my family!
It's going to be difficult
to cancel the wedding.
I'm just making most of
my time as your fiance.
Huh? Fiance? Am I
really his girlfriend?
Oh?
Why are you staring like that?
Haven't you realized
that when a man and woman
are arranged to wed,
they are actually
engaged to each other?
Miss?
Are you alright?
Mother wouldn't mind
if I take you for the day.
Help! This isn't part of the plan.
I shouldn't be falling for Juanito.
Miss? Are you alright?
Just focus on your mission, Carmela.
Oh!
These accessories are beautiful!
Accessories?
What do women like these days?
Oh... For Helena, right?
Helena likes red roses.
She likes reading, embroidery,
and generally being affectionate.
Good thing I interviewed Helena last time.
What can you say
about this necklace?
My grandmother gave it to me.
She said I should give it to the
woman I'm ready to give my heart to...
Without second thoughts.
Is this real gold?
Are you serious?
Wow.
How about you, Miss Carmelita?
What kind of gift do you like?
Hmm...
I like things that are made with effort.
Nothing that can be
bought or acquire easily.
That's tough.
Of course.
I'm not easily appeased.
Good day, Mr. Juanito.
I'm glad to see you here.
Good day to you as well, Trinidad.
How are you?
I'm doing good, Sir.
Excuse me for asking, Mr. Juanito.
But I just want to know
if the lady you're with
is the youngest daughter of
Don Alejandro Montecarlos?
Yes.
She's Miss Carmelita Montecarlos.
I am pleased to meet you, Miss Carmelita.
Now, I can surely say
that what they've been saying is true.
That you possess such a
stunningly beautiful face.
Gee, thanks.
Thank you.
Miss,
if you would allow me...
I want to make use of this moment.
To ask you a favor.
From me?
What do you need?
I just want you to ask your father
if it's possible to keep the
price of rent from rising...
For the workers of your plantation.
My husband's meager salary
wouldn't be able to afford it.
He is one of your many workers.
Wait, what?
Is Don Alejandro oppressing his workers?
Sure. I'll let Father know.
Thank you so much, Miss.
You are a blessing from Heaven.
Have you chosen anything, Miss?
If you would ask me, Miss...
I think this will suit you.
Seriously? I would look
like a household ornament.
I'm sure it'll look good on her, Sir.
I will buy this. For her.
And if you would allow it...
I want you to take this
as a token of gratitude
for visiting our humble town.
And for passing on our
request to your father.
Thank you.
Thank you as well, Miss.
Here's the letter.
Is this from Helena?
You don't believe me?
What I'm doing here is volunteer work.
I don't get anything
from the two of them.
I should charge delivery fee next time.
Thank you.
Good afternoon, Don Alejandro.
The sun is setting, dear boy.
I'll be going then, Don Alejandro.
Miss Carmelita.
Alright. Take care on your way home.
Maybe Don Alejandro is thinking
we're passing love letters to each other.
Father?
May I talk to you?
What is it, dear? Sit down.
Earlier, in the other town...
A merchant talked to me.
She asked to pass
on a request to you.
If it's possible not to raise the
price of rent for our workers.
Who said this to you?
It is important to listen and
respond to the woes of our workers.
It was Trinidad
from the other town.
I am glad that you care for
the welfare of our workers.
Very well...
I will cut their rent next week.
Thank you, Father.
Miss.
This is from Miss Helena.
It's in Spanish? I don't understand this.
What's written in the letter, Miss?
A poem.
What is it about?
Uh...
A poem about love.
She's asking to edit her...
To revise her poem.
It's early to sleep.
In fairness, I'm getting used
to sleeping early. It's fine.
- Carmelita.
- Oh?
What are you still doing here?
We are going somewhere important.
Where are we going?
Didn't you receive the
letter Helena sent you?
There. That's the
invitation for her birthday.
You don't have any plan to attend?
What? I didn't know
it was an invitation.
You'll go, understand?
What's your gift to Helena?
I'll just give this
to her as my gift.
This party is crazy!
She really prepared for her birthday.
But it's so boring, there's
not even any drinks.
Miss, do you wish to change
how we first met?
Can I ask for your name?
Perhaps this is
as beautiful as the
light of the moon.
Why does Juanito have to tell me
that they are going out on a date?
I have an information
that Eduardo is going to
serenade Maria later at night
Juanito will be playing the guitar
and Ignacio will also come.
Juanito.
Since we're already here,
you can also serenade Helena.
Did I heard that right?
A song for Helena?
I wanted you to be
the first to know.
I'm planning to make
our relationship official.
Is this what you're looking for?
Oh yes, This is it!
Seven months has
already passed since I left.
But it seems like,
you've already
forgotten about me.
Leandro.
Since when did you comeback
to San Alfonso?